Kavel Rao

(425) 365-7637 • kavelrao@uw.edu

I'm a freshman at the University of Washington passionate about software and aerospace technology. I have experience programming in Python, Java, C, and C++. I also have strong technical writing and editing skills and enjoy working in teams and leading peer groups.

Education

Expected graduation 2024 University of Washington College of Engineering – Seattle, WA

- Intended major: Computer Engineering
- GPA: 3.97
- Washington NASA Space Grant Scholar

Graduated 2020 Newport High School – Bellevue, WA

- Received high school diploma with honors
- GPA: 4.00, 12 AP classes, ACT: 35

Experience

2020 – present Husky Satellite Lab: Software Engineer

- Work across subteams to create fully integrated systems and test platforms
- Build software systems for a planned lunar satellite
- Designing PID control system
- Program embedded systems microcontrollers using C and C++

2020 – present HiScore Learning: Test Prep Teacher

- Teach 2.5 hour, 25 student classes
- Give feedback to students and communicate with parents
- Create practice testing material

Fall 2020 NASA L'Space Mission Concept Academy: Computer Engineer

- Researched and wrote a Preliminary Design Review for a lander mission to investigate seismic activity on Saturn's moon Enceladus

2016 – 2020 Newport High School Rocketry Club: President, Senior Mentor

- Took club to Nationals in the American Rocketry Competition 2 years in a row
- Established structure of club, increased membership from 25 to 50 in 2 years
- Fundraised \$3000, including recurring annual \$1200 grant from Aerojet Rocketdyne
- Mentored new rocketeers and started middle school outreach programs

Awards and Achievements

2018 & 2019 - National Finalist, The American Rocketry Competition 2018 - Level 1 High Power Rocketry Certification 2020 - National Qualifier, NAQT Quiz Bowl 2019 - All-Northwest Honor Band 1st Trombone, National Association for Music Education 2016 - Black Belt, Shotokan Karate	2020	- First Place, The American Rocketry Competition Presentation Contest
2020 - National Qualifier, NAQT Quiz Bowl 2019 - All-Northwest Honor Band 1st Trombone, National Association for Music Education	2018 & 2019	- National Finalist, The American Rocketry Competition
2019 - All-Northwest Honor Band 1st Trombone, National Association for Music Education	2018	 Level 1 High Power Rocketry Certification
,	2020	- National Qualifier, NAQT Quiz Bowl
2016 - Black Belt, Shotokan Karate	2019	- All-Northwest Honor Band 1st Trombone, National Association for Music Education
	2016	- Black Belt, Shotokan Karate

Skills

- Programming Languages: Python, Java (intermediate); C, C++ (beginner)
- Web Design: Full stack web development using MySQL, Python, Javascript, HTML, CSS (beginner)
- Technical Writing: Strong writer and editor in professional environments